Eugene Sokolov

New York, NY

347.901.9097 eugsokolov@gmail.com eugsokolov.github.io

Full stack engineer with 5 years of software development experience looking to join a high growth team and solve interesting software and data problems that matter. I enjoy designing robust systems and having my code automate!

Skills

Languages: Python (Flask, Django, pandas), SQL, NoSQL (Redis, Mongo), Javascript (Node, React/Redux, Angular/NGRX) Design: database design, automation, REST/RPC, git, Linux, AWS, Terraform, machine learning

Experience

Flatiron Health New York, NY

2020-

Senior Software Engineer

- Collaborating with product/design teams to create a self service oncology research data ETL system
- Leading and coaching small team of engineers to build new features and follow software best practices
- Built and released several features which automate functionality in project pipelines, saving users time spent by 10x
- Serving as a team architect to set team norms and improve the developer experience

The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art New York, NY

2018-

Adjunct Professor (part time) - ECE 464: Databases

- Teaching a graduate level course exposing students to theoretical and practical applications in modern database development
- Topics include: relational data model, SQL, ORMs, database design, NoSQL, "Big Data"

Adaptive Management/Knoema New York, NY

2019-2020

Senior Software Engineer

- Developed and supported Oasis, an alternative data infrastructure and ETL ingestion system, processing TB of data daily
- Decreased client response times 1000x by redesigning an 'ingestion database' schema
- Developed and supported DataMonster, a data management and visualization Flask web application
- Increased productivity 20x by improving developer coding experience, PR processes, testing, and dev ops
- Spearheaded successful Python 2.7 to 3.8 transition (and increased test coverage)
- Increased QA productivity exponentially by managing a team of 6 contractors to build a Selenium regression test framework
- \bullet Increased revenue 15% by suggesting a major feature and wrote product specs, giving more fine grained introspection and control over charting tools
- Increased client usage and decreased download time 4x by refactoring Pypi library which provides API access to data

Hudson River Trading New York, NY

2016-2019

Software Developer (Series 57 certified)

- Monitored live trading weekly, tended to operational issues in a fast paced environment, and debugged mission critical software handling hundreds of millions of trades daily
- Worked with all areas of the firm to streamline company procedures and operational requests
- Developed, built, and maintained various Python processes and automated workflows
- Decreased corporate action issues 10x by automating procedures and improving override capabilities
- Created system to automate ETF order placement, managing notional values of \$1-10 million daily

Projects and Research

On Software Development Product Management: Feature Selection and Model Analysis of Predicting Jira Issue Attributes: Masters Thesis 2016-2017

• Researched Jira to determine factors that drive issue completion time, priority, and resolution using regression methods

The Influence of the Medial Prefrontal Cortex on a Socially Influenced Deception Task as Determined via Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation: 7th Annual Sense to Synapse Conference 2017

• Built programs for psychology experiments analyzing the medial prefrontal cortex and its affect on human social patterns

Education

The Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art New York, NY

• Masters of Engineering (M.Eng.), Electrical Engineering 4.0 / 4.0

2017

• Bachelors of Engineering (B.Eng.), Electrical Engineering 3.5 / 4.0

2016